export const LEATHERWORKA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The leather articles that the early man used were",
A: "drums and slings.",
B: "puppets and drums.",
C: "puppets and vellum.",
D: "slings and vellum",
answer: "A. drums and slings.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In early coaches, leather took the place of",
A: "axles.",
B: "springs.",
C: "tyres.",
D: "wheels.",
answer: "B. springs.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Various textures on leather are achieved by",
A: "embossing, fraying and incising.",
B: "glazing, buffing and graining.",
C: "rubbing, drying and graining.",
D: "stamping, embossing and fraying",
answer: "A. embossing, fraying and incising.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is a major characteristic of the butt?",
A: "Tensility",
B: "Thickness",
C: "Softness",
D: "Strength",
answer: "D. Strength",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The commonly used agent for dehairing is",
A: "Ash",
B: "Dung",
C: "Lime",
D: "Salt",
answer: "C. Lime",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Motifs are usually employed in",
A: "carving.",
B: "colouring.",
C: "embossing.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "C. embossing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of these fasteners is fixed to leather articles without the use of another material?",
A: "Buckle",
B: "Hook and eye",
C: "Press stud",
D: "Zip",
answer: "C. Press stud",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The most commonly used leather items are",
A: "armours.",
B: "containers.",
C: "footwears.",
D: "garments.",
answer: "C. footwears.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Dyes are said to be fast if they",
A: "are very expensive.",
B: "do not fade easily.",
C: "have many uses.",
D: "make the leather shine",
answer: "B. do not fade easily.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A leather surface is rendered non-porous by",
A: "buffing.",
B: "coating.",
C: "lacquering.",
D: "painting.",
answer: "C. lacquering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Stippling on leather produces",
A: "dots.",
B: "holes.",
C: "perforations.",
D: "slits.",
answer: "A. dots.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. An example of a relief design on leather is",
A: "carving.",
B: "scorching.",
C: "staining.",
D: "stippling.",
answer: "A. carving.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The content weight of the bag is considered in attaching a",
A: "flap.",
B: "gusset.",
C: "handle.",
D: "pocket.",
answer: "C. handle.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A sword is appropriately kept in a",
A: "holster.",
B: "pannier.",
C: "quiver.",
D: "sheath.",
answer: "D. sheath.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Identify a leather covered articles in the following;",
A: "leather bag.",
B: "leather wall hanging.",
C: "leather shoe.",
D: "leather walking stick.",
answer: "C. leather shoe.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following operations gives leather a uniform thickness?",
A: "Glazing",
B: "Scouring",
C: "Shaving",
D: "Staking",
answer: "C. Shaving",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Putrefied portions of a hide",
A: "devalue the leather.",
B: "enhance dyeing.",
C: "facilitate tanning.",
D: "soften the leather",
answer: "A. devalue the leather.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Grain leather is the same as",
A: "chamois leather.",
B: "shoe leather.",
C: "sole leather.",
D: "suede leather.",
answer: "D. suede leather.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The layer of the skin next to the wool is referred to as the",
A: "corium.",
B: "derma.",
C: "flesh.",
D: "grain.",
answer: "C. flesh.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Fittings are used in leatherwork for",
A: "binding and stitching.",
B: "decorating and assembling.",
C: "finishing and sewing.",
D: "sewing and assembling.",
answer: "D. sewing and assembling.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Rough edges of leather are hidden with",
A: "bevelling.",
B: "in-laying.",
C: "skiving.",
D: "thonging.",
answer: "A. bevelling.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of these articles is rawhide most appropriate for?",
A: "Bellow",
B: "Belts",
C: "Drums",
D: "Footwear",
answer: "C. Drums",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Slit holes are made for",
A: "assembling.",
B: "carving.",
C: "sewing.",
D: "thonging",
answer: "C. sewing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Giving a water-proof treatment to an article makes it",
A: "breakable. Â·",
B: "durable.",
C: "flexible.",
D: "Malleable",
answer: "B. durable.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of these knives is used to produce designs on leather?",
A: "Head knife",
B: "Skiving knife",
C: "Stanley knife",
D: "Swivel knife",
answer: "D. Swivel knife",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The raw material for the tanner is",
A: "grain.",
B: "leather.",
C: "leatherette.",
D: "rawhide.",
answer: "D. rawhide.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Perforations of varied sizes are created on leather with",
A: "awl.",
B: "chisel.",
C: "drive punch.",
D: "rotary punch.",
answer: "D. rotary punch.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A ring and pivot are part of",
A: "a dee-ring.",
B: "an eyelet.",
C: "a rivet.",
D: "a swivel.",
answer: "D. a swivel.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Leather retains its surface flatness after",
A: "carving.",
B: "modelling.",
C: "peeling.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "A. carving.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. An ideal leather workshop must be",
A: "airy.",
B: "humid.",
C: "shady.",
D: "sunny.",
answer: "A. airy.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Leather surfaces are imitated by",
A: "glazing.",
B: "graining.",
C: "painting.",
D: "spraying",
answer: "C. painting.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Examples of animals from which hides are obtained include",
A: "cows and goats.",
B: "horses and zebras.",
C: "snakes and crocodiles.",
D: "steers and sheep.",
answer: "D. steers and sheep.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The tool used in fixing eyelets is the",
A: "hammer.",
B: "mallet.",
C: "modellers.",
D: "setters.",
answer: "D. setters.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]